

Bhavin Amin

Cloud & Systems Engineer Philadelphia, PA



(484) 919-7713



bhavin.amin@gmail.com



bhavinamin.github.io

No one likes reading an essay!
For more info and code samples,
check out my site, reach out on
LinkedIn or give me a ring!

About Me

"Have you tried turning it on and off again?"

Although it has a high win rate, fourteen years of sysadmin experience has taught me that phrase is just not enough to keep business tech up and running. I believe a modern approach to information systems requires embracing secure identity access via single sign-on, using devops and automation for infrastructure deployments and mastering a patience and eagerness to keep up with the always-evolving landscape . I can bring those skills and more to the party.

Experience

2024 - present

Cloud Engineer @ Jefferson Health

Adopted Azure DevOps and CI/CD workflows to stand up infrastructure via Terraform, notably VMs, Azure Kubernetes Service clusters and Azure Container Registries. Also compiled docker images and deployed them to said clusters. Created and managed service principals, app registrations, Entra ID groups and users.

2021- 2023

Lead Sys Admin @ Voyager Digital

Implemented Okta SSO and worked with our secops team to architect MFA rules, device trust, group assignments and more. Integrated 25+ web apps with Okta to provide password-less authentication for our users including Jira, Slack, Tableau and AWS. Also set up HR and SCIM provisioning to help automate new employee onboarding. Other responsibilities include managing MacBooks via JAMF and interacting with various APIs for mass system or account actions.

2012-2021

Sr Endpoint Admin @ Penn Medicine

Ancient tech here. Hosted apps on Citrix and provisioned them to users via delivery groups. For anything not hosted on Citrix, I packaged and deployed apps via Microsoft SCCM to their desktops. Deployed and updated operating system images via SCCM and extensively used Powershell to manage user accounts within Active Directory (disabling them, moving them to different groups, etc).

Education

2004 - 2008

University of Pittsburgh

Bachelor of Arts in Political Science and Film Studies

Weren't expecting that huh? Turns out the film industry has a very rocky job market.

Skills

What I do	What I Use	
IAM	Okta / Entra	
Scripting	Python, PS	
Cloud	Terraform	
Endpoint	JAMF / SCCM	

Interests



